

# **SAGAR WADKE**

Mechanical Engineer

## **Personal Information**



03/04/1995



Goethestraße 31, Wedel, 22880 Germany.



German (B1) | English (C1) | Hindi | Marathi



+49 15753652948



sagarwadke03@gmail.com

# **Programming Skills**





Python



R Programming



**MATLAB** 

#### CAD & CAE Skills



SolidWorks



SpaceClaim



Creo



AutoCad



ANSYS Workbench & Fluent

#### **Other Skills**



SAP



**LATEX** 



JIRA



Confluence



MS Office (Excel, Word & PowerPoint)



Adobe (Illustrator & Photoshop)

# **PROFILE SUMMARY**

Mechanical Engineer with 3+ years of experience in the design, fabrication, and developing high-precision optical measurement and manufacturing systems. Strong background in design, tolerancing, and manufacturing processes. Proficient in camera calibration, image processing, system integration, and data analysis. Effective in international, high-pressure environments, consistently delivering optimized solutions for performance, cost, and quality.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Oct 2022 - Present Working Student, Image Quality

Trioptics GmbH (Jenoptik AG).

- Contributed to product design and development for MTF measuring systems in Visual, UV, MWIR and LWIR spectrum for ImageMaster Universal and Afocal
- Designed and validated proof-of-concept for an advanced intrinsic camera calibration performance and distortion measuring system.
- Prepared programming scripts for measurement of samples, in-house calibration and testing of devices used in production.
- **Automated** certification and documentation workflows with Excel VBA and Python, cutting documentation time by 75% and boosting efficiency.

## Feb 2019 - Feb 2020 Quality Engineer

Paras Space and Defence Technologies Pvt Ltd (Optics Division).

- Performed optical metrology on products such as aspheric, diffractive, and asphero-diffractive lenses, gratings, and mirrors preparing detailed final reports.
- Collaborated cross-functional with teams machining, polishing, and coating to optimize the manufacturing workflow and ensure production.
- Developed an algorithm in Excel to automatically validate product parameters, resulting in zero defects and significant time savings.

#### **EDUCATION**

2021 - 2024

# **MSc. Mechanical Engineering and Management**

- Hamburg University of Technology
- Specialization: Product Development and Planning
- 1.8

2013 - 2017

### **B.E.** (Mechanical Engineering)

- University Of Mumbai
- 2.0

## ACHIEVEMENTS AND EXTRA CURRICULARS

- Successfully lead a multidisciplinary team to develop a concept for Automated Rotor House Fastening robot sponsored by Siemens Gamesa under the Fishing for Experience program organized at TUHH
- Secured first place in innovation workshop for developing innovative care concept for cows suffering from digital dermatitis (Mortellaro) at TUHH (2023)
- Successfully lead a team of international students to solve European Consortium of Innovative Universities Water Challenge. (2022)